

Muhammad Moiz Siddique

Phone number: (+92) 3062890575 (Mobile) | Email address:

muhammadmoiz0087@gmail.com | **Website:** https://muhammadmoiz200099.github.io/ |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-moiz-siddique-b09261252/

Skype: live:muhammadmoiz2000991 | **Address:** Pakistan (Home)

ABOUT ME

I am a passionate and determined candidate who has transformed his hobby into a career, seeking an opportunity with a reputable organisation. I am an accomplished Software Engineer with over 5+ years of experience leading projects by acting as a Senior Engineer, Developer and Programmer Analyst.

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2023 - 12/2023 (remote) Scarborough, Canada

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER EXCEL PROS INC.

- Engaged in working with modern **Javascript** frameworks/libraries and other Programming Languages like Python, Go Lang and Java, etc.
- Integrated **third-party tools** and components into applications.
- Developed robust, scalable, modular and API-centric infrastructures.
- · Manage & update the CI/CD pipeline, review and debug code and working with AWS and Github Pipeline
- Collaborated with clients to define solution requirements and manage JIRA tickets.
- Writing project/application structure and discussion on **Design Patterns**.
- Tested troubleshooting methods and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team
- Implement modern/best programming techniques and infrastructures such as **SOLID principles**, **Imperative Programming**, **Object-oriented Programming**, **Functional Programming**.

01/07/2022 - 30/11/2022 (remote) London, United Kingdom

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER BLACK LION INVESTMENT GROUP, INC.

- I'm working as **team lead** on a project.
- I worked with modern javascript frameworks and libraries such as React JS, Node JS, Flutter etc.
- Organize a daily scrum meeting to identify, prioritize and execute tasks in the software development life cycle
- · Manage and Checkin JIRA tickets.
- Tested troubleshooting methods and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team
- Implement modern/best programming techniques and infrastructures such as **SOLID principles**, **Object-oriented Programming**, **Functional Programming**, etc.

07/06/2022 - 31/08/2022 (on site) Karachi, Pakistan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER THE DESIGNRY

- I worked with modern javascript frameworks and libraries such as Angular, React IS, Node:Express IS, etc.
- Manage & update the deployments with AWS EC2.
- · Writing Test's for the applications.
- Developed application servers having scalable, change acceptance, modular and security features.

01/06/2019 – 31/05/2022 (on site) Karachi, Pakistan

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER ALGORACK INC.

- Working on Full Stack Technologies such as Angular, React Js, Node Js, Next Js, Native Script, Ionic, Flutter and React Native.
- Improved application designs with addition of new features and infrastructure.
- Integrated Build systems for example **Bable** and **Webpacks**.
- Handle API Integration and Wekhooks
- Optimised test cases to maximize success of manual software testing.
- Created successful E2E & Unit test scripts to manage automated feature testing using Jest, Karma, Jasmine, react-testing-tool etc.
- Handle deployments on Cloud platforms such as AWS and Github actions for deployment pipelines.
- Integrate Payment gateways using third party tools such as Stripe API.
- · Worked with SQL and noSQL databases such as Mongodb, MySQL, SQL server, Postgress SQL.
- Handle client meetings and manage JIRA tickets.
- Completed various project few are from the scratch and I'm the lead developer having a small team to work on.

- I worked alongside some of the most skilled programming professionals.
- I learnt (Dot) Net programming language.
- I was exposed to the software infrastructure used in such a large sized professional company.
- Thoroughly understand how data centers are utilized in such large organizations works.
- This further helped me increase my **team-working creditability** working within a professional IT department and understanding the **workplace dynamic**.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

16/10/2017 - 18/06/2021 Karachi, Pakistan

BACHELOR'S OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Mohammad Ali Jinnah University

Address Main Shahrah e Faisal, 22-E, Block-6, PECHS, 75400, Karachi, Pakistan | Final grade A

2015 - 2017

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE Islamia Government Science College

Address Karachi, Sindh, Pakistan | Final grade D

2013 - 2015

SCHOOL SECONDARY CERTIFICATE Habib Public School

Address Karachi, Sindh, Pakistan | Final grade A+

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PROJECTS

SOCIAL CHAMP (DOT) IO - (https://www.socialchamp.io/) Tech Stack: Angular, Node Js, Mongo db, Native Script. Responsibilities: Design and develop new modules, maintain and manage existing application including bug fixes, analyze requirement and estimate ETAs. For Mobile Application we used the Native script,

THINK EVOLVE SOLVE - (https://thinkevolvesolve.ie/) Tech Stack: Angular, Node Is, Azure.

Responsibilities: I'm the **team lead** on this project having **2 members team** to Design, develop and manage frontend, backend and **data pipelines** and **cloud architectures** with **efficient processing** and management of large amounts of data, also **develop interfaces / APIs** for data exchange in Node Js.

Bright Development - (https://bright-development.com/); Tech Stack: **React JS, Node Js, Mongo db.**Responsibilities: **Team lead**, manage daily **workflow**, work on client proposed modules and make sure to provide high quality work, write **test for every new module**, manage and maintain **CI/CD pipeline**, **daily scrum** with team members, handle **client meeting**, manage **JIRA** and assigned work to team.

BridgeStone - (https://www.bridgestone.com/) Tech Stack: Angular, Java (Spring Boot), SQL, AWS, All Social Media developer, Flutter, APIs.

Responsibilities: My responsibilities on this projects is to manage the existing feature and implement the new user stories with respect to designs that client give to me. Also, Frontend deployment on a dedicated server is mine responsibility. **For Mobile Application**, we use the flutter.

Black Lion App - (https://www.blacklionapp.xyz/) Tech Stack: React JS, Node Js, Mongo db, Redis, AWS, All Social Media developer APIs, Flutter, others.

Responsibilities: Worked from scratch on this project and i'm the Team lead, having a 4 person team to manage, estimate ETAs, organize a daily scrum meeting to identify, prioritize and execute tasks, daily client meeting, understand client stories and assigned work to the team accordingly, manage and maintain CI/CD pipelines, using SaaS manage to communicate with cloud services, review and debug code, manage Github actions, update and maintain story board, review and merge pull request on Github. For Mobile Application, we used the flutter.

Excel Pros - (https://www.excel-pros.com/) Tech Stack: Next JS, Node Js, Mongo db, AWS.

Responsibilities: I write the **base structure of this website** and then work on few page. I was actually suppose to work on other application which are running under Excel Pros.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

08/06/2022

JavaScript: Core And Advanced Techniques - Udemy: Online Courses

Link https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-0c1bcfe1-3e17-4c6d-944a-e2151435ab66/

16/08/2021

Programming in Javascript language Certification - Hackerrank

Link https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/4e9849d2073a

12/08/2020

Speed Programming (Code Jam) - Google

Link https://codingcompetitions.withgoogle.com/codejam/certificate/summary/00000000001857b3

11/04/2020

Certification for Problem Solving Algorithms - Hackerrank

Link https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/f48c8558d84d

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND PLATFORMS

JAVASCRIPT / TYPESCRIPT / JAVA / PYTHON / C / C++ / C# / DOT (NET) / GO LANG / PHP / LARAVEL / HTML / CSS / DJANGO / FLASK / TENSERFLOW

WEB AND APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

ANGULAR / REACT JS / NODE JS / STENCIL JS / NEST JS / NEXT JS / VUE JS / REACT NATIVE / FLUTTER / AWS / GOOGLE CLOUD / GOOGLE API'S / OAUTH / OAUTH2 / SOCKETS / MACHINE LEARNING / AI / CI-CD PIPELINES / GITHUB WORKFLOWS / EC2 INSTANCES / AWS LAMBDA / AWS SQS / AWS S3 / GITHUT / JIRA / BITBUCKET / HEROKU / NETLITY / VERCEL / DOCKER.

DATABASE SKILLS

MONGO DB / MY SQL / SQL SERVER / POSTGRESS SQL / REDIS / ORACLE / DYNAMO DB

LANGUAGES

Urdu (Native) / English (Fluent) / Turkish (Basics)